<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Ambrose Field</title>
    <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Ambrose Field</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Architexture Series: evidence-based, bespoke architectually linked compositions.</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/archproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/archproject/</guid>
      <description>The Architexture Series Musicc The Architexture Series of works makes use of the sonic profile of buildings as an evidence base for musical composition.
Detailed links between the musical score and the unique spatial and acoustic characteristics of the performance site are embedded within these compositions. Modelling the acoustic in this way during the musical composition process can help achieve a closer bond between the notes on the page and the sound perceived by listeners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architexture I, for 10 part choir</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/architexture1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/architexture1/</guid>
      <description>18 mins | 2012 | 10-part Choir (SSAATTBarBarBB)
  About the composition Architexture I is a choral music work in which the acoustic of the performance venue is designed into the substance of the music itself. This is done through the use of three-dimensional acoustic analysis techniques to inform a traditional “pen and paper” composition process. The harmony, the speed of vocal entries, and the way they overlap each other in time, are sculpted with knowledge of the architectural acoustics of the space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architexture II, for 6 part choir</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/architexture2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/architexture2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;20 mins |  2015 |  6-part Choir (SSAATB)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Architexture II was composed for a public augmented reality
experience. Over 600 people attended the premier at St. Mary&amp;rsquo;s York,
where we re-constructed the acoustic St Mary&amp;rsquo;s would have had were it
still standing, and performed Architexture II - a vocal work
specifically designed to provide an immersive and accurate interaction
with with the re-created space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/archproject/&#34;&gt;this description&lt;/a&gt; of the architexture project itself for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ambrosefield.github.io/ox-hugo/ambrosefield_architexturegig.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ambrosefield.github.io/ox-hugo/ambrosefield_architexturegig.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/KZWeDSgkPDg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;musical-construction&#34;&gt;Musical Construction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Architexture II, a 20 minute vocal work for six part choir  exploits the specific architectural acoustics characteristics of a heritage building which is no longer present today. As this is new music, and not a &amp;lsquo;historical re-construction&amp;rsquo;, it is possible to bring the public experience closer to the reality of the past in new ways: the composition Architexture II is designed to closely match &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; physical site. If we had selected generic repertoire from the same period to perform within a simulated acoustic, it would not be possible to fully &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that the works really had a tight relationship with the exact building with which we were working, or indeed how choral directors of the day would have articulated them due to the limitations of written documentary evidence from the period and the issue that authentic performance scholarship whilst a valuable resource can not fully capture the actual sounding experience of interacting with a particular space from this period on a detailed and nuanced level. A powerful case for new composition for heritage applications emerges as these relationships can be constructed from the present day in order to present a more rigorously evidenced view of the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frozen Reflection, Sleeping Buffalo: Piano and mechanical resonators</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/frozenreflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/frozenreflection/</guid>
      <description>19 mins | 2017 | Piano Solo  Megumi Masaki
About the work Frozen Reflection, Sleeping Buffalo uses EBows - electromechanical resonating devices, not as drones in their own right, but to provoke delicate and unusual timbres from sustained piano chords. The EBows continually vibrate a string as if it had infinite sustain (and are often used by guitarists for this purpose). The piano pedal in this work forms a kind of &amp;lsquo;envelope&amp;rsquo; control, opening up and closing down this resonance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Assembly Unit Series: rethinking score design as reproducible research</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/saunit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/saunit/</guid>
      <description>2019 | Scores for a rehearsal process
Information A series of pieces where the musicians structure an off-line design process themselves. The score describes these activities, rather than a performance.
   The performers credit themselves as composers for these pieces under a creative commons license.
 Scoring the rehearsal process, not the performance The purpose of this work is to investigate what a score for a &amp;lsquo;rehearsal process&amp;rsquo; might be (rather than a score aimed at a &amp;lsquo;realisation&amp;rsquo; of a &amp;lsquo;performance&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRCAM OM composers&#39; book 3: process for matching notated composition to acoustic profiles.</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/compresonance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/compresonance/</guid>
      <description>2017 | Book Chapter
  Book Chapter: Field, A: Composing for the resonance: finding new relationships between architecture and musical composition
This chapter documents research which led to the creation of the Architexture Series of vocal works. The article describes a set of techniques to show, on a stave, the effect of reverberation of the venue. A composition can be planned out to take account of the acoustic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transmission Cycle, for Tenor and Strings: 40 mins, large-scale work for Jazz.ro</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/transmissioncycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/transmissioncycle/</guid>
      <description>40 minutes | String quartet and solo Tenor | 2014
An epic journey in sound, starting from simple premises, with melodic threads slowly unwinding unbroken over the course of 40 minutes. The piece is scored for amplified string quartet and solo tenor. The string lines build slowly then fade in and out of focus, creating a shimmering haze of harmony above which the tenor line floats. Fragments of text from Ovid&amp;rsquo;s Metamorphosis are delivered as if they were part of a distant news broadcast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anagram for tenor and electronics - Premier the Old Customs House, Tampere</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/anagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/anagram/</guid>
      <description>with Film by Michael Lynch
Anagram is a follow-up project to Being Dufay and premièred at the Old Customs House, Tampere vocal festival in 2013. The work explores different ways of using pre-existing text to that within Being Dufay, searching for what I&amp;rsquo;ll term the minimum trace: what is just enough to make a link to a pre-existing work, yet not so much that the piece overtly borrows material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantaform Series for Solo Flute in reverberant spaces</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/quantaform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/quantaform/</guid>
      <description>C Flute, 40 mins duration
Background and new 2019 Realisation Quantaform Series is an unusual 20 movement work for solo flute where each movement is precisely matched to the acoustics of the site in which it is to be performed. Each of the twenty movements is written to match a different acoustic space. The choice of which movements to perform, and in what order, is up to the performer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pod Twoją Obronę, for 25 part choir</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/podtwoja/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/podtwoja/</guid>
      <description>Pod Twoją Obronę (2013) | for 25 solo voices | Recorded live in Gdansk Conductor: Jan Łukaszewski   Pod Twoją Obronę was commissioned by the Polish National Chamber Choir Polski Chor Kameralny to mark the 80th birthday anniversary of composer Henryk Górecki. This work matches the large, resonant acoustics of the Kościół św. Katarzyny in Gdansk (in which the piece was performed) to the detailed part writing which occurs within the piece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 1971: Imperfect forms - Ken Kirschner Remixed</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/kirschner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/kirschner/</guid>
      <description>Imperfect Forms - The Music of Kenneth Kirschner Remixed I was invited to collaborate in the re-mixing of Ken Kirshner&amp;rsquo;s beautiful music. But instead of remixing the work, I decided to intervene at an earlier stage and re-perform it prior to electronic manipulation.
This work is an extract from a longer unpublished set of pieces, Kirschner Variations. The work explores how borrowing (acknowledged, and with permission) from a living composer might feel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frozen Voyagers, electroacoustic sounds, high-order ambisonics spatial audio</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/frozenvoyagers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/frozenvoyagers/</guid>
      <description>Frozen Voyagers premiered at the MUTEK festival, Canada in 2014 in cinechamber : a spectacular 360 degree surround audio and video auditorium curated by Naut Humon from Recombinant Media Labs. The piece is designed to maximise the spatial qualities of the venue and sound projection system. I&amp;rsquo;m aiming to try and capture a sense of &amp;lsquo;frozen time&amp;rsquo; through the huge amount of swirling audio activity: standing within this sonic vortex might be a little like being in the eye of the storm: stillness and extreme motion at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>