<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>acoustics on Ambrose Field</title>
    <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/categories/acoustics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in acoustics on Ambrose Field</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ambrosefield.github.io/categories/acoustics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Architexture II, for 6 part choir</title>
      <link>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/architexture2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/architexture2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;20 mins |  2015 |  6-part Choir (SSAATB)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Architexture II was composed for a public augmented reality
experience. Over 600 people attended the premier at St. Mary&amp;rsquo;s York,
where we re-constructed the acoustic St Mary&amp;rsquo;s would have had were it
still standing, and performed Architexture II - a vocal work
specifically designed to provide an immersive and accurate interaction
with with the re-created space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://ambrosefield.github.io/research/archproject/&#34;&gt;this description&lt;/a&gt; of the architexture project itself for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ambrosefield.github.io/ox-hugo/ambrosefield_architexturegig.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://ambrosefield.github.io/ox-hugo/ambrosefield_architexturegig.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/KZWeDSgkPDg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;musical-construction&#34;&gt;Musical Construction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Architexture II, a 20 minute vocal work for six part choir  exploits the specific architectural acoustics characteristics of a heritage building which is no longer present today. As this is new music, and not a &amp;lsquo;historical re-construction&amp;rsquo;, it is possible to bring the public experience closer to the reality of the past in new ways: the composition Architexture II is designed to closely match &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; physical site. If we had selected generic repertoire from the same period to perform within a simulated acoustic, it would not be possible to fully &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that the works really had a tight relationship with the exact building with which we were working, or indeed how choral directors of the day would have articulated them due to the limitations of written documentary evidence from the period and the issue that authentic performance scholarship whilst a valuable resource can not fully capture the actual sounding experience of interacting with a particular space from this period on a detailed and nuanced level. A powerful case for new composition for heritage applications emerges as these relationships can be constructed from the present day in order to present a more rigorously evidenced view of the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>